[
  {
    "subject": "html",
    "quiz": [
      {
        "id": 1,
        "question": "What does HTML stands for?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "Hypertext Machine language.",
            "b": "Hypertext and links markup language.",
            "c": "Hypertext Markup Language.",
            "d": "Hightext machine language"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "Hypertext Markup Language."
      },
      {
        "id": 2,
        "question": "How is document type initialized in HTML5.?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "</DOCTYPE HTML>",
            "b": "</DOCTYPE>",
            "c": "<!DOCTYPE HTML>",
            "d": "</DOCTYPE html>"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "<!DOCTYPE HTML>"
      },
      {
        "id": 3,
        "question": "Which of the following HTML Elements is used for making any text bold ?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "<p>",
            "b": "<i>",
            "c": "<li>",
            "d": "<b>"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "<b>"
      },
      {
        "id": 4,
        "question": "Which of the following HTML element is used for creating an unordered list?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "<ui>",
            "b": "<i>",
            "c": "<em>",
            "d": "<ul>"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "<ul>"
      },
      {
        "id": 5,
        "question": "Which of the following characters indicate closing of a tag? ",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": ".",
            "b": "/",
            "c": "//",
            "d": "!"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "/"
      },
      {
        "id": 6,
        "question": "What is the font-size of the h1 heading tag?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "3.5 em",
            "b": "2.17 em",
            "c": "2 em",
            "d": "1.5 em"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "2 em"
      },
      {
        "id": 7,
        "question": "How many heading tags are there in HTML5?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "2",
            "b": "3",
            "c": "5",
            "d": "6"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "6"
      },
      {
        "id": 8,
        "question": "How many attributes are there in HTML5?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "2",
            "b": "4",
            "c": "1",
            "d": "None of the above"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "None of the above"
      },
      {
        "id": 9,
        "question": "Which of the following attributes is used to add link to any element?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "link",
            "b": "ref",
            "c": "href",
            "d": "newref"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "href"
      },
      {
        "id": 10,
        "question": "What is the purpose of using div tags in HTML?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "For creating Different styles.",
            "b": "For creating different sections.",
            "c": "For adding headings.",
            "d": "For adding titles."
          }
        ],
        "answer": "For creating different sections."
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "subject": "css",
    "quiz": [
      {
        "id": 1,
        "question": "Which of the below is the abbreviation of CSS ?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "Cascade sheets style",
            "b": "Color and style sheets",
            "c": "Cascading style sheets",
            "d": "color style sheets"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "Cascading style sheets"
      },
      {
        "id": 2,
        "question": "Which of the following is the correct syntax to add the external stylesheet in CSS?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "< style src = quiz.css >",
            "b": " < style src = 'quiz.css' >",
            "c": "<stylesheet> quiz.css </stylesheet>",
            "d": "<link rel='stylesheet' type='quiz/css' href='quiz.css'>"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "<link rel='stylesheet' type='quiz/css' href='quiz.css'>"
      },
      {
        "id": 3,
        "question": "Which of the below CSS properties is used to change the background color of CSS ?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "bg color",
            "b": "color-background",
            "c": "background-color",
            "d": "color"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "background-color"
      },
      {
        "id": 4,
        "question": "Which of the below CSS class is used to change the text color of CSS ?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "background-color",
            "b": "color",
            "c": "color-background",
            "d": "None of the above"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "color"
      },
      {
        "id": 5,
        "question": "Which of the below is the correct syntax to put a line over text in CSS?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "text-decoration: line",
            "b": "text-decoration: none",
            "c": "text-decoration: overline",
            "d": "text-decoration: underline"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "text-decoration: underline"
      },
      {
        "id": 6,
        "question": "Which below property of CSS is used to set the indentation of the first line in a block of text ?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "text-indent property",
            "b": "text-underlne-property",
            "c": "text-decoration none",
            "d": "text-overflow property"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "text-indent property"
      },
      {
        "id": 7,
        "question": "Which element is used to represent the transparency of an element in CSS ?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "Hover",
            "b": "Opacity",
            "c": "Transparent",
            "d": "Overlay"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "Opacity"
      },
      {
        "id": 8,
        "question": "Which of the below CSS property is used to add a stroke in the text ? ?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "text-stroke",
            "b": "text-transform",
            "c": "text-decoration",
            "d": "None of the above"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "text-stroke"
      },
      {
        "id": 9,
        "question": "Which property in CSS is responsible for setting the difference between two lines ?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "min-height property",
            "b": "max-height property",
            "c": "line-height property",
            "d": "None of the above"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "line-height property"
      },
      {
        "id": 10,
        "question": "Which of the below the property is used to overflow the text in CSS?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "text-shadow",
            "b": "text-stroke",
            "c": "text-overflow",
            "d": "text-decoration"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "text-overflow"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "subject": "javascript",
    "quiz": [
      {
        "id": 1,
        "question": "Inside which HTML element do we put the JavaScript?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "<javascript>",
            "b": "<js>",
            "c": "<src>",
            "d": "<script>"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "<script>"
      },
      {
        "id": 2,
        "question": "Where is the correct place to insert a JavaScript?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "Both the head section and the body section are correct",
            "b": "The head section",
            "c": "The body section",
            "d": "None of the above"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "Both the head section and the body section are correct"
      },
      {
        "id": 3,
        "question": "Is it necessary for the external script file to contain a <script> tag?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "Yes",
            "b": "No",
            "c": "Depends on the type of include",
            "d": "None of the above"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "No"
      },
      {
        "id": 4,
        "question": "What is the correct syntax for referring to an external script called 'gfg.js'?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "<script name='gfg.js'>",
            "b": "<script href='gfg.js'>",
            "c": "<script src='gfg.js'>",
            "d": "None of the above"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "<script src='gfg.js'>"
      },
      {
        "id": 5,
        "question": "How many ways are there with which we can declare a variable in javascript?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "Only one",
            "b": "Three",
            "c": "Infinitely many",
            "d": "None of the above"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "Three"
      },
      {
        "id": 6,
        "question": "Is a variable named 'apple' same as 'Apple' in javascript?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "Yes",
            "b": "No",
            "c": "Only when we use 'strict'",
            "d": "None of the above"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "No"
      },
      {
        "id": 7,
        "question": "Which of the following variable names are correct according to javascript? (Multiple Choices may be correct)",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "let 1name;",
            "b": "let #name;",
            "c": "let _name;",
            "d": "let name 1;"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "let _name;"
      },
      {
        "id": 8,
        "question": "Which of the following represent falsy values in javascript",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "false",
            "b": "' '",
            "c": "undefined",
            "d": "All of the above"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "All of the above"
      },
      {
        "id": 9,
        "question": "Which of the following represent truthy values in javascript",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "true",
            "b": "{}",
            "c": "[]",
            "d": "All of the above"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "All of the above"
      },
      {
        "id": 10,
        "question": "What will be the output of the following code snippet let data='false'; data?console.log('first statement'):console.log('second statement');",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "first statement",
            "b": "Second statement",
            "c": "Can't say",
            "d": "None of the above"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "first statement"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "subject": "python",
    "quiz": [
      {
        "id": 1,
        "question": "nameList = ['Harsh', 'Pratik', 'Bob', 'Dhruv'] print (nameList[1][-1])",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "r",
            "b": "b",
            "c": "D",
            "d": "k"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "k"
      },
      {
        "id": 2,
        "question": "Who developed Python Programming Language?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "Wick van Rossum",
            "b": " Rasmus Lerdorf",
            "c": "Guido van Rossum",
            "d": "Niene Stom"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "Guido van Rossum"
      },
      {
        "id": 3,
        "question": "Which type of Programming does Python support?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "object-oriented programming",
            "b": "structured programming",
            "c": "functional programming",
            "d": "all of the mentioned"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "all of the mentioned"
      },
      {
        "id": 4,
        "question": "Is Python case sensitive when dealing with identifiers?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "no",
            "b": "yes",
            "c": "machine dependent",
            "d": "none of the mentioned;"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "yes"
      },
      {
        "id": 5,
        "question": " Which of the following is the correct extension of the Python file? ",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": ".python",
            "b": ".pl",
            "c": ".py",
            "d": ".p"
          }
        ],
        "answer": ".py"
      },
      {
        "id": 6,
        "question": " Is Python code compiled or interpreted?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "Python code is both compiled and interpreted",
            "b": " Python code is neither compiled nor interpreted",
            "c": "Python code is only compiled",
            "d": " Python code is only interpreted"
          }
        ],
        "answer": " Python code is both compiled and interpreted"
      },
      {
        "id": 7,
        "question": " All keywords in Python are in _________",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "Capitalized",
            "b": "lower case",
            "c": "UPPER CASE",
            "d": "None of the mentioned"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "None of the mentioned"
      },
      {
        "id": 8,
        "question": "4 + 3 % 5",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "7",
            "b": "2",
            "c": "4",
            "d": "1"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "7"
      },
      {
        "id": 9,
        "question": "Which of the following is used to define a block of code in Python language?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "Indentation",
            "b": "Key",
            "c": "Brackets",
            "d": "All of the mentioned"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "Indentation"
      },
      {
        "id": 10,
        "question": "Which keyword is used for function in Python language?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "Function",
            "b": "def",
            "c": "Fun",
            "d": "Define"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "def"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "subject": "datastructure",
    "quiz": [
      {
        "id": 1,
        "question": "How many passes does an insertion sort algorithm consist of?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "N",
            "b": "N-1",
            "c": "N+1",
            "d": "N<sup>2<sup>"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "N-1"
      },
      {
        "id": 2,
        "question": "Which of the following algorithm implementations is similar to that of an insertion sort?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "Binary heap",
            "b": "Quick sort",
            "c": "Merge sort",
            "d": "Radix sort"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "Binary heap"
      },
      {
        "id": 3,
        "question": "What is the average case running time of an insertion sort algorithm?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "O(N)",
            "b": "O(N log N)",
            "c": "O(log N)",
            "d": "O(N<sup>2</sup>)"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "O(N<sup>2</sup>)"
      },
      {
        "id": 4,
        "question": "What is the average number of inversions in an array of N distinct numbers?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "N(N-1)/4",
            "b": "N(N+1)/2",
            "c": "N(N-1)/2",
            "d": "N(N-1)/3"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "N(N-1)/4"
      },
      {
        "id": 5,
        "question": "What is the running time of an insertion sort algorithm if the input is pre-sorted? ",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "O(N<sup>2</sup>)",
            "b": "O(N log N)",
            "c": "O(N)",
            "d": "O(M log N)"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "O(N)"
      },
      {
        "id": 6,
        "question": " What will be the number of passes to sort the elements using insertion sort? 14, 12,16, 6, 3, 10",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "6",
            "b": "5",
            "c": "7",
            "d": "1"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "5"
      },
      {
        "id": 7,
        "question": "For the following question, how will the array elements look like after second pass? 34, 8, 64, 51, 32, 21",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "8, 21, 32, 34, 51, 64",
            "b": "8, 32, 34, 51, 64, 21",
            "c": "8, 34, 51, 64, 32, 21",
            "d": "8, 34, 64, 51, 32, 21"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "8, 34, 64, 51, 32, 21"
      },
      {
        "id": 8,
        "question": "Which of the following real time examples is based on insertion sort?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "arranging a pack of playing cards",
            "b": "database scenarios and distributes scenarios",
            "c": "arranging books on a library shelf",
            "d": "real-time systems"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "arranging a pack of playing cards"
      },
      {
        "id": 9,
        "question": " In C, what are the basic loops required to perform an insertion sort?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "do- while",
            "b": "if else",
            "c": "for and while",
            "d": "for and if"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "for and while"
      },
      {
        "id": 10,
        "question": " Which of the following options contain the correct feature of an insertion sort algorithm?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "anti-adaptive",
            "b": " dependable",
            "c": "stable, not in-place",
            "d": "stable, adaptive"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "stable, adaptive"
      }
    ]
  },
  {
    "subject": "java",
    "quiz": [
      {
        "id": 1,
        "question": "Who invented Java Programming?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "Guido van Rossum",
            "b": "James Gosling",
            "c": "Dennis Ritchie",
            "d": "Bjarne Stroustrup"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "James Gosling"
      },
      {
        "id": 2,
        "question": "Which statement is true about Java?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "Java is a sequence-dependent programming language",
            "b": "Java is a code dependent programming language",
            "c": "Java is a platform-dependent programming language",
            "d": "Java is a platform-independent programming language"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "Java is a platform-independent programming language"
      },
      {
        "id": 3,
        "question": "Which component is used to compile, debug and execute the java programs?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "JRE",
            "b": "JIT",
            "c": "JDK",
            "d": "JVM"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "JDHK"
      },
      {
        "id": 4,
        "question": "Which one of the following is not a Java feature?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": " Object-oriented",
            "b": "Use of pointers",
            "c": "Portable",
            "d": "Dynamic and Extensible"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "Use of pointers"
      },
      {
        "id": 5,
        "question": "Which of these cannot be used for a variable name in Java? ",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "identifier & keyword",
            "b": "identifier",
            "c": "keyword",
            "d": "none of the mentioned"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "keyword"
      },
      {
        "id": 6,
        "question": "What is the extension of java code files?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": ".js",
            "b": ".txt",
            "c": ".class",
            "d": ".java"
          }
        ],
        "answer": ".js"
      },
      {
        "id": 7,
        "question": "Which environment variable is used to set the java path?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "MAVEN_Path",
            "b": "JavaPATH",
            "c": "JAVA",
            "d": "JAVA_HOME"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "JAVA_HOME"
      },
      {
        "id": 8,
        "question": "Which of the following is not an OOPS concept in Java?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "Polymorphism",
            "b": "Inheritance",
            "c": "Compilation",
            "d": " Encapsulation"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "Compilation"
      },
      {
        "id": 9,
        "question": " What is not the use of “this” keyword in Java?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": " Referring to the instance variable when a local variable has the same name",
            "b": " Passing itself to the method of the same class",
            "c": "Passing itself to another method",
            "d": "Calling another constructor in constructor chaining"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "Passing itself to the method of the same class"
      },
      {
        "id": 10,
        "question": "Which of the following is a type of polymorphism in Java Programming?",
        "options": [
          {
            "a": "Multiple polymorphism",
            "b": "Compile time polymorphism",
            "c": "Multilevel polymorphism",
            "d": "Execution time polymorphism"
          }
        ],
        "answer": "Compile time polymorphism"
      }
    ]
  }
]
